<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rishi Sadhir&#39;s personal blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rishi Sadhir&#39;s personal blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Bayes: Part 1</title>
      <link>/2020/02/08/intro-to-bayes-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/08/intro-to-bayes-part-1/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I will give you a relatively nontechnical introduction to Bayesian statistics. Bayesian methods are getting more and more popular and there are many tools out there to apply it. In this example, we&#39;ll use a computationally simple example to pin down concepts and jargon. In a follow-up post, I will introduce the basics of Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) and the Metropolis–Hastings algorithm to solve more complex problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea, Oxen, and Discrete Parameters</title>
      <link>/2020/02/01/tea-oxen-and-discrete-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/01/tea-oxen-and-discrete-parameters/</guid>
      <description>This is a retelling of Richard McElreath’s story about tea, oxen, and discrete parameters in Stan. In a Chinese village, children love tea but can only enjoy it after stabling their oxen. The problem is, children are liars sometimes and its up to us enforce the rules.
 You are the village enforcer of oxen customs… Each evening, you must determine which children have properly stabled their oxen. For many houses, you can see whether or not the ox is stabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Rishi Sadhir is a senior data science manager at Wayfair. Rishi&#39;s passions include adventure travel, yoga, meditation, and learning. This blog contains articles about statistics, computer science, leadership, and business. All views expressed are his own and not reflective of his employer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T-Test is not BEST</title>
      <link>/2019/12/31/t-test-is-not-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/31/t-test-is-not-best/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we explore the task of comparing groups of measurements. We’ve all heard about the T-Test, but Bayesian statistics offers an interesting alternative. Let’s talk about how “Bayesian estimation supersedes the t-test” (Kruschke, 2013).
Preliminaries In this post, we’ll encode Kruschke’s methods in STAN and use it to compare action move ratings versus comedy movie ratings. The code shown below is also available in python here along with the supporting CSV.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>