<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Rishi Sadhir&#39;s personal blog</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Rishi Sadhir&#39;s personal blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing Uncertainty</title>
      <link>/2020/02/28/embracing-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/28/embracing-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite things about being a data scientist is running experiments. Often, data science teams will run a lot of experiments that aim to measure the same thing - Usually because we only have some short window to learn something or some other constraints. The purpose of most experiments is to recover an effect size for something we care about. When the experiment is over, we have typically measured this effect size with some uncertainty (like a standard error) about this measurement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea, Oxen, and Discrete Parameters</title>
      <link>/2020/02/01/tea-oxen-and-discrete-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/01/tea-oxen-and-discrete-parameters/</guid>
      <description>This is a retelling of Richard McElreath’s story about tea, oxen, and discrete parameters in Stan. In a Chinese village, children love tea but can only enjoy it after stabling their oxen. The problem is, children are liars sometimes and its up to us enforce the rules.
 You are the village enforcer of oxen customs… Each evening, you must determine which children have properly stabled their oxen. For many houses, you can see whether or not the ox is stabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T-Test is not BEST</title>
      <link>/2019/12/31/t-test-is-not-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/31/t-test-is-not-best/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we explore the task of comparing groups of measurements. We’ve all heard about the T-Test, but Bayesian statistics offers an interesting alternative. Let’s talk about how “Bayesian estimation supersedes the t-test” (Kruschke, 2013).
Preliminaries In this post, we’ll encode Kruschke’s methods in STAN and use it to compare action move ratings versus comedy movie ratings. The code shown below is also available in python here along with the supporting CSV.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>